# Tai Fa Tang

+44 785 385 3558 taifatang@hotmail.com

# **PROFILE**

Real programmers count from <u>0</u>. A leap of faith was taken 6 years ago when Tai found a natural flare within software development, in which developed into great passion. From this, Tai abandoned his biomedical background taking him back to zero and tackled programming heads on. Being entirely self-taught, Tai takes programming very seriously both at work and at home and always sees beyond the scope. Software developers like to solve problems. If there are no problems readily available, Tai will create his own problems!

#### **PORTFOLIO & LEARNING PROFILE**

- Personal website & Portfolio: https://taifatang.github.io
- LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tai-fa-tang-732491a4/

#### **SKILLS & ACHEIVEMENTS**

# MCSD: Web Applications Solutions Developer

- MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional
- MS: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
   MS: Programming in C#

  PASS
  PASS

# NVQ Level 2 Spectator safety Security, City & Guilds

NVQ Level 2 Spectator safety Security, City & Guilds

PASS

#### **Hackathon – Charity Special Effect 2017 Hacker Games**

• First place winner of the Charity hosted "Hacker Game" from a small team of 5 formed within ASOS

## **Training**

•	Security Compass – CSP103 – Secure Software Design	Up to date
•	Security Compass – SEC101 – OWASP Top 10	Up to date
•	Microsoft – Service Fabric Hack Fest	2017
•	Cigital – Security OWASP Top 10	2017
•	Codurance – Software Craftsmanship 12 weeks programme	2017

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Trainline, 120 Holborn, EC1N 2TD, London

**2021 - Present** 

• Senior Software Engineer

# Trainline, 120 Holborn, EC1N 2TD, London

2018 - 2021

- Agile Developer
  - Languages: C#, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, SQL
  - Tools: Jira, Kibana, New Relic, Pager Duty, TeamCity
  - Framework: AWS, Net Core, Vue.is,
  - Event sourcing with HATEOAS for payment phase management
  - Leading card security code tokenisation, 3DSv2 roll out across 15+ channels
  - Leading fraud and payment projects, facilitating discussions with stakeholders
  - Curating documentations and charting for business metrics
  - PCI compliant development and sensitive data tokenisation
  - Trialling mission team, cross functions collaboration
  - Out of hours support

Tai Fa Tang

ASOS.com, Greater Londo	n House, Ham	pstead Rd, NW	17FB, London
-------------------------	--------------	---------------	--------------

2016 - 2017

- Software Engineer
- A.I Chatbot
  - Languages: C#
  - Tools: VSTS, App Insight, CosmoDb, Octopus
  - Framework: Azure , Net Core, Service Fabric
  - A.I. Natural Language Processing
  - Facebook Messenger Platform Development
  - Full software development life cycle
  - Internal tech start-up (prototyping, MVP, weekly sprint, user testing)

#### Authentication & Identification

- Languages: C#, JavaScript
- Tools: TFS, Azure Management Studio, NServiceBus, Service Pulse, IIS
- Framework: Azure, Net Framework,
- Customer Profile, Sign on and Log out
- Customer JWT token management
- OAuth, OpenID Connect, Tokenised API Access
- Security first cloud based Micro-services
- Acceptance Test Driven Development (Specflow)

# Onalytica, Unit 2, Baden Place, Crosby Row, SE1 1YW, London

2015 - 2016

- Software Engineer
  - Languages: C#, CSS(SASS&LESS), HTML5, JavaScript, SQL
  - Tools: VivfyScrum, Trello, Elastic Search Azure, App Insight, IIS
  - Framework: AWS, Azure, Net Framework, Angular.js, Backbone.js, NodeJs,
  - Maintaining existing and developing new product
  - Learning JavaScript and relevant frameworks from ground zero
  - Ingesting large volume of data from Twitter's GNIP API.
  - Agile and start-up culture
  - Full stack involvement

## Boots Opticians, 44-46 Regent Street, W1B 5RA, London

2014 - 2015

Optical Consultant

## Longdan, 25 Hackney Road, E2 7NX, London

2014 - 2014

Administrator

# **EDUCATION**

#### Junior C# & .NET Developer, Just IT

2015 - 2016

- Great in depth knowledge of C# and .Net Framework
- Good understand of OOP, SOLID and TDD principle
- Understanding Core function of ASP.NET, Entity Framework, LINQ and SQL
- knowledge of Bootstrap, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3 for web development

## MSc Forensic Medical Science, Queen's Mary University

2013 - 2014

BSc (HONS) Biomedical Science Honours, Middlesex University

2010 - 2013

2

#### **INTERESTS**

- Crafting SOLID code adhering to Manifesto for Software Craftsmanship's standard
- Seeking the best of other programming paradigms. Swift, Typescript, C++ etc
- Explore mobile development, UI & UX designs with Sketch and XCode

Tai Fa Tang